Miscellany Magazine Collection 1929-1943 MSS.261
Fales Library and Special Collections
Miscellany Magazine Collection
1929-1943
1929-1930
Fales Library and Special Collections
The Miscellany
MSS.261
0.25 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box.
Miscellany Magazine ran from 1929 - 1931 and comprised 6 issues. The magazine featured poetry, essays, and film, art, and literature reviews. It was based in New York City. The collection contains correspondence, advertisers, contributions, subscriber lists, and reviews of Miscellany Magazine. There is also one issue of the magazine.
Box 1
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically in two series.
Biographical / Historical
Miscellany Magazine ran from 1929 - 1931 and comprised 6 issues. It was edited by Frederick W. Dupee, Geoffrey T. Hellman, George L. Kingsland Morris, and Dwight MacDonald. The magazine featured poetry, essays, and film, art, and literature reviews. It was based in New York City.
Custodial History
The collection had been housed at NYU's Fales Library from at least the 1990s. The provenance of the collection is unclear.
Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence, advertisers, contributions, subscriber lists, and reviews of Miscellany Magazine. There is also one issue of the magazine.
Magazines (Periodicals); The Miscellany (New York, N.Y.); Macdonald, Dwight; Dupee, Frederick W., 1904-; Morris, George L. K., 1905-1975; Hellman, Geoffrey, 1907-
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Aiken, Conrad; Afard, Walter R.; Allen, Hervey; Arevalo, Betty Wison; Arvin, Newton, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bakchy, Alexander; Barnes, Clare Jr.; Blackmur, R.P., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Briscoe, Louise; Brooke, Tucker; Brooks, Cleanth; Brown, Hamilton, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bryan, Hamish; Buckner, M.M.; Burke, Kenneth, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Caldwell, Erskine; Carey, Marjorie; Carter, Hodding, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charvat, William; Clevas, Mary A.; Coughlin, Miss E.B., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cranford; Davidson, Donald; Davis, H.L.; DeJong; David Cornel, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Delehanty, Thornton; Dinsmore; Ellion, R.; Finch, Everett L., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Foster, Thomas Jr.; Gallatin; Gottfried, Manfred; Gould, Wallace, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Grattam, G. Hartley; Grey, J.C.; Griswold; Haase, Paul G., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hansen, Harry; Heap, Jane; Hess, Peggy, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hoffrek; Ada Mae; Humphries, Rolf; Jeffers, Robinson; Jones, Llewellyn, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Kapustin, Harry; Kelly, Kathryn H.; Kirsten, Lincoln, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred; Lambert, George; Loftus, John; Lowe, Robert Liddell, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lowenstein, M.; Mangun, Sherry; Marcley, George C., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Milburn, George; Moloff, Pete; Munson, Gorham B., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Newton, George A.; Nubs, Brairg; O'Brien, Edward; Old Corner Book Store, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Phelps, William Lyon; Preston, George Hyde; Robson, Bill; Rosenfield, Paul, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sampson, Ashley; Sheridan, Kathleen; Smart, C.A.; Smith, Logan Pearsall, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stewart, Laura; Swanson, Minerva; Tate, Elizabeth; Tharp, Willard, 1930; 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Vogel, Joseph; Wheeler, Dinsmore; Wheeler, Richard Page; Williams, William Carlos, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Wilson, Edmund; Winters, Yvor; Witherspoon, Alexander M., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified / Illegible, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series II: Administrative Papers
  - Advertising, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Contributors, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Potential Subscribers list, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Reviews, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Subscribers, 1929-1943 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Miscellany - Vol. 1, No. 6, March 1931 (Box 1, Folder 29)